Catheryn C Millares

Langtad City of Naga Cebu Philippines | Mobile: 88937046 | Email: Catheryn.millares@yahoo.com

Objective

Ability to maintain focus in any setting, Detail-oriented and able to demonstrate composure under pressure in a fast-moving work setting. Comfortable working independently or within a highly collaborative team environment. Excellent collaboration skills and experienced with working as a team with peers in a professional learning community. Ability to analyze data obtained from assessment results and interpret accordingly.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Dedicated and HardworkingPatient CareWork ManagementCreative ThinkingNeeds AnalysisMedication and TreatmentProblem SolvingMultitaskingInterpersonal Communications

WORK EXPERIENCE

NTUC My First Skool, May 2022 - Present

Assistant Teacher

Key Responsibilities:

- Collaborating with faculty members daily, attending staff meetings and partaking in all school sponsored
 activities.
- Providing accurate assessment of student learning abilities, designing and implementing standards-based and developmentally appropriate instruction to ensure meeting individual student needs.
- Individualizing and adapted content to ensure equal access to all students.
- Providing both group and individual instruction in a manner that effectively used classroom time.
- Maintaining appropriate guidelines for student behavior.
- Preparing, administering, scoring, and recording assessments.
- Formulating and implementing curriculum, as well as coordinating events such as open house, demonstrations, and more.
- Developing curriculum, preparing and utilizing oral and visual presentations, evaluating student progress, and build relationships with parents to update them on student behavior, performance, and development.
- Continually facilitating a favorable learning environment in which students are motivated and driven by their own successes and accomplishments.
- Utilizing a variety of teaching strategies, such as whole/small group instruction, team teaching, cooperative learning, inquiry-based learning, literacy-based instruction, hands-on learning, and project-based learning.
- Assisting teachers in preparing Individualized Educational Program (IEP) and Individualized Transition Plan (ITP).
- Ensuring safety of the learning by providing an environment conducive for learning.

NTUC Health Cooperative Limited, Jul 2019 – May 2022

Nursing Aide

Key Responsibilities:

- Administered medications or treatments, such as catheterizations, suppositories, irrigations, enemas, massages, or douches, as directed by a physician or nurse.
- Answered patient call signals, signal lights, bells, or intercom systems to determine patients' needs.
- Applied clean dressings, slings, stockings, or support bandages, under direction of nurse or physician.
- Assisted nurses or physicians in the operation of medical equipment or provision of patient care.
- Cleaned and sanitized patient rooms, bathrooms, examination rooms, or other patient areas.
- Collected specimens, such as urine, feces, or sputum.
- Communicated with patients to ascertain feelings or need for assistance or social and emotional support.
- Monitored vital signs of the residents like blood pressure, pulse rate, respiratory rate, body temperature, and oxygen saturation. Informs the staff nurse for abnormalities.

- Documented in the NHELP the results of the vital signs taken.
- Monitored intake and output of the residents like food, urine, feces.
- Supervised Next of Kin (NOK) of residents and staff when performED Antigen Rapid Test (ART)

PRIOR WORK EXPERIENCE

Call Center Agent back support, Wipro PTE Limited, Jun 2016 to May 2018 Caregiver, Asilo Dela Milagrosa (home for the aged), Jul 2011 to Aug 2013

CREDENTIALS

Bachelor of Science (M.SC.) in Nursing, University of San Jose Recoletos, Philippines, 2016

TRAINING AND SEMINARS

BCLS + AED provider(BVM), Singapore Heart foundation, Singapore, Dec 2021 – Dec 2023 CPR+AED, HMI Institute, Singapore, Dec 2019 – Dec 2021

INTERNSHIP

Perpetual Succour Hospital, Eversley Child, 2014 – 2016 Sanitarium hospital, Saint Anthony Mother and Child, 2014 – 2016 Hospital, Cebu City Medical Center, 2014 – 2016

Assigned Wards: Male and Female ward, Delivery Room, Operating Room, Private Rooms, Intensive Care Unit, Pediatrics Ward, Ob ward, Emergency Room

Asilo De La Milagrosa, 2012 – 2013 Assigned Ward: General Ward

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth: June 16 1992

Gender: FemaleNationality: Filipino